A Guide to the James Branch Cabell Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #5298
James Branch Cabell Collection 1915-1946
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
5298
ca. 300 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Gift, 1956 December 31
Item Listing
- Manuscripts
  - Suggestions, ca. 1917; TMsS, 3 p.
  - Review of Jurgen by Joseph Hergesheimer, [1920]; TMs, 3 p.
  - "Exit", 1921 Jun; Typescript, 7 p.
  - The Jewel Merchants, ca. 1921; Typescript, 30 p.
  - The Lineage of Lichfield, with autograph corrections, 1922; Typescript, 9 p.
  - The Lineage of Lichfield, with autograph corrections, [1922]; Galley proof, 16 p.
  - Printers directions for Cream of the Jest, [1922]; AMs, 2 p.
  - Proofs of Cream of the Jest, with autograph corrections, [1922]; Proofs, 2 p.
  - The Music From Behind the Moon, ca. 1926; Typescript, 34 p.
  - Lineage of Lichfield, n.d.; AMs, 2 p.
  - "Ascent of Vraidex," fragment from Figures of Earth, n.d.; AMs, 2 p.
  - Revision for Jurgen, n.d.; Typescript, 3 p.
  - Draft of "Jurgen in Limbo," revised and annotated in Cabell's hand, Typescript, 5 p.
  - Beyond Life, TMs, ca. 200 p.
    [Inscribed to Guy Holt; with autograph corrections.]
- Letters
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1915 Apr 29; ALS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1916 Mar 1; ANS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1916 Apr l9; ALS, 4 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1916 Jul 8; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1916 Dec 20; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to Guy Holt, 1916 Dec 30; TLS, 1 p.
  - Guy Holt to James Branch Cabell, 1917 Jan 3; TLS (carbon), 4 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1917 Jan 7; TLS, 3 p.
  - [ Guy Holt] to James Branch Cabell, 1917 Jan 12; TL (carbon), 3 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1917 Jan 15; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1917 Apr 16; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to Guy Holt, 1917 May 26; TLS, 1 p.
  - [ Guy Holt] to James Branch Cabell, 1917 May 31; TL (carbon), 2 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to Guy Holt, 1917 Jun 9; TLS, 2 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1917 Jun 23; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1917 Jul 25; TLS, 2 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1917 Aug 30; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to Guy Holt, 1917 Sep 20; TLS, 1 p.
  - [ Guy Holt] to James Branch Cabell, 1917 Sep 25; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1917 Sep 28; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to Guy Holt, 1917 Oct 3; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to Guy Holt, 1917 Nov 3; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1917 Nov 10; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1917 Dec 3; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1917 Dec 14; TLS, 1 p.
  - Guy Holt to James Branch Cabell(fragment), [1917 Dec]; ALS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1918 Jan 5; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1918 Jan 9; TLS, 2 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1918 Jan 17; TLS, 3 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1918 Feb 22; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1918 Apr 5; TL, 2 p.
  - [ Guy Holt] to James Branch Cabell, 1918 Apr 10; TL (carbon), 2 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1918 Apr 13; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to Guy Holt, 1918 Apr 27; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1918 May 9; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1918 May 14; TLS, 1 p.
  - [ Guy Holt] to James Branch Cabell, 1918 May 21; TL (carbon), 2 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1918 Jun 5; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1918 Jun 12; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1918 Jul 11-12; ALS, 2 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1918 Sep 14; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1918 Sep 28; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1918 Sep 29; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1918 Oct 22; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1918 Dec 11; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1919 Jan 6; TLS, 2 p.
  - [ Guy Holt] to James Branch Cabell, 1919 Jan 7; TL (carbon), 2 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1919 Jan 29; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1919 Feb 22; TLS, 2 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1919 Mar 15; TLS, 1 p.
  - [ Guy Holt] to James Branch Cabell, 1919 Mar 21; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1919 Apr 8; TLS, 2 p.
  - [ Guy Holt] to "Oh Perverse and Wicked Man!" [ James Branch Cabell], 1919 Apr 11; TL, 2 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to "My dear Dame Lisa", 1919 Apr 16; TLS, 2 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1919 Apr 23; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1919 Apr 26; TLS, 1 p.
  - [ Guy Holt] to James Branch Cabell, 1919 May 22; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - Guy Holt to James Branch Cabell, [1919 May]; TL (carbon), 2 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1919 Aug 19; ALS, 1 p.
  - Hugh Walpole to [ Guy Holt?], 1919 Nov 7; ALS, 4 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1919 Nov 15; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1919 Dec 6; TLS, 3 p.
  - Gilbert Cannan to [Guy] Holt(located in scrapbook, p. 10), 1919 Dec 15; TL (copy), 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1919 Dec 20; TLS, 1 p.
  - [ Guy Holt] to James Branch Cabell, 1919 Dec 23; TL, 3 p.
  - Louis Untermeyer to [Guy] Holt, 1919 Dec 23; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1920 Jan 3; ALS, 2 p.
  - Christopher Morley to Guy [Holt], 1920 Jan 12; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1920 Jan 17; TLS, 1 p.
  - H. L. Mencken to [Guy] Holt, [1920] Jan 20; TLS, 1 p.
  - Gilbert Cannan to [Guy] Holt(located in scrapbook, p. 11), 1920 Jan 20; TL (copy)
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt(fragment), 1920 Jan 20; TL, 1 p.
  - Wilson Follett to [Guy] Holt(located in scrapbook, p. 14-15), 1920 Jan 23; TL (copy)
  - Sinclair Lewis to [Guy] Holt(located in scrapbook, p. 7), 1920 Jan 23; TL (copy)
  - William Rose Benet to [Guy] Holt, 1920 Jan 23; ALS, 1 p.
  - H. L. Mencken to [Guy] Holt, [1920] Jan 24; TLS, 1 p.
  - Louis Untermeyer to [Guy] Holt, 1920 Jan 26; TLS, 1 p.
  - Guy Holt to Henry A. Lappin, 1920 Jan 28; TL (carbon), 2 p.
  - Gilbert Cannan to Guy Holt, 1920 Jan 28; TL (copy), 1 p.
  - Paul Jordan Smith to Guy Holt, 1920 Jan 30; TLS, 1 p.
  - Leary & Goodbody to Guy Holt, 1920 Jan 31; TLS, 1 p.
  - Sinclair Lewis to Guy Holt, 1920 ca. Jan; TLS, 3 p.
    [Enclosing TLS, 1920 Jan 23, Sinclair Lewis to [Guy] Holt re: the charges of indency against
    Jurgen
    . ]
  - Leary & Goodbody to Robert M. McBride & Co., 1920 Feb 2; TLS, 1 p.
  - [Guy] Holt to W. V. Goodbody, 1920 Feb 3; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - Barrett H. Clark to Guy Holt, 1920 Feb 3; ALS, 1 p.
  - George Sterling to Guy Holt, 1920 Feb 7; ALS, 3 p.
  - Ernest A. Boyd to [Guy] Holt, 1920 Feb 10; TLS, 2 p.
  - Joseph Hergesheimer to [Guy] Holt, 1920 Feb 10; TLS, 2 p.
  - Sidney Howard to Robert M. McBride, 1920 Feb 13; TLS, 1 p.
  - Stephen Vincent Benet to [Guy] Holt, 1920 Feb 14; ALS, 2 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to Guy Holt, 1920 Feb 16; TLS, 1 p.
  - Amelie Rives Troubetzkoy& Pierre Troubetzkoy to Guy Holt, 1920 Feb 17; TLS, 2 p.
  - Edward Hale Bierstadt to Robert M. McBride, 1920 Feb 20; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Hopper to [Guy] Holt(located in scrapbook, p. 21), 1920 Feb 26; TL (copy), 1 p.
  - Ellis P. Oberholtzer to Robert M. McBride, 1920 Mar 1; ALS, 1 p.
  - Guy Holt to Ernest A. Boyd, 1920 Mar 9; TL (carbon), 2 p.
  - T. R. Smith to Guy Holt, 1920 Mar 9; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1920 Mar 15; TLS, 1 p.
  - H. L. Mencken to [Guy] Holt, [1920] Mar 15; TLS, 1 p.
  - Guy Holt to H. L. Mencken, 1920 Mar 17; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - H. L. Mencken to [Guy] Holt, [1920] Mar 19; TLS, 1 p.
  - Kate Langley Bosher to Guy Holt(located in scrapbook, p. 5), 1921 Mar 21; TL (copy)
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1920 Mar 29; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1920 May 5; TLS, 1 p.
  - [ Guy Holt] to James Branch Cabell, 1920 May 6; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - [ Guy Holt] to James Branch Cabell, 1920 May 8; TL (carbon), 2 p.
  - Wilson Follett to [Guy] Holt, 1920 May 11; ALS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to Guy Holt, 1920 May 11; TLS, 1 p.
  - [Guy] Holt to Wilson Follett, 1920 May 12; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1920 May 27; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1920 Jun 5; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1920 Jul 4; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1920 Aug 2; ALS, 4 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1920 Aug 11; ALS, 2 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1920 Oct [3 or 8]; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1920 Nov 8; TLS, 2 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1920 Dec 14; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1920 Dec 21; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1920 Dec 31; TLS, 1 p.
  - Extract from letter from George Moore, [1920]; TL (copy), 1 p.
  - F. Scott Fitzgerald to Guy Holt, ca. 1920; ALS, 1 p.
  - Burton Rascoe to [Guy] Holt, ca. 1920; TLS, 2 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1921 Jan 15; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1921 Jan 18; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1921 Jan 25; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1921 Jan 26; TLS, 1 p.
  - H. L. Mencken to [Guy] Holt, [1921] Feb 24; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1921 Mar 11; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1921 Apr 12; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1921 Apr 21; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1921 Apr 29; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1921 May 4; TLS, 1 p.
  - H. L. Mencken to [Guy] Holt, [1921] May 27; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1921 May 31; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1921 Jun 11; TLS, 2 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1921 Jun 20; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1921 Jul 6; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1921 Sep 27; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1921 Oct 4; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1921 Oct 18; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1921 Oct 24; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1921 Nov 3; TLS, 1 p.
  - [ Guy Holt] to James Branch Cabell, 1921 Nov 4; TL (carbon), 3 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1921 Nov 10; TLS, 1 p.
  - H. L. Mencken to [Guy] Holt, [1921] Dec 9; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1921 Dec 14; TLS, 2 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1921 Dec 26; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1922 Jan 3; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1922 Jan 27; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1922 Feb 10; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1922 Mar 18; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1922 May 2; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1922 May 17; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1922 Jun 17; TLS, 1 p.
  - [ Guy Holt] to James Branch Cabell, 1922 Jun 20; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1922 Aug 10; ALS, 2 p.
  - [ Guy Holt] to James Branch Cabell, 1922 Aug 14; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1922 Aug 28; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1922 Sep 27; TLS, 1 p.
  - [Guy] Holt to James Branch Cabell, 1922 Oct 3; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Garrard] Glenn, 1922 Oct 5; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1922 Oct 8; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1922 Oct 16; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1922 Oct 19; TLS, 1 p.
  - [Guy] Holt to James Branch Cabell, 1922 Oct 20; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1922 Oct 23; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1922 Oct 25; TLS, 1 p.
  - [Guy] Holt to James Branch Cabell, 1922 Oct 26; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Robert M.] McBride, 1922 Nov 18; TLS, 10 p.
    [Enclosing Guy Holt's Foreword to
    , revised by Cabell, with carbon.]
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1922 Nov 24; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1922 Dec 16; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1923 Jan 6; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1923 Feb 3; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1923 Feb 20; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1923 Mar 28; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1923 Apr 4; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1923 Apr 7; TLS, 1 p.
  - [Guy] Holt to James Branch Cabell, 1923 Apr 19; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1923 May 1; TLS, 2 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1923 May 5; TLS, 1 p.
    [On verso, 1923 May 8, TL carbon, 1 p., [Guy] Holt to James Branch Cabell. ]
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1923 May 12; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1923 May 19; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1923 May 26; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1923 May 26; TLS, 1 p.
  - [Guy] Holt to James Branch Cabell, 1923 May 29; TL (carbon), 2 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1923 Jun 2; TLS, 1 p.
  - [Guy] Holt to James Branch Cabell, 1923 Jun 5; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1923 Jun 26; TLS, 2 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1923 Jul 7; ALS, 2 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [ Guy Holt?], 1923 Aug 21; ANS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1923 Oct 12; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1923 Nov 10; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1923 Dec 29; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, [1923]; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1924 Jan 5; AL, 1 p.
  - [Guy] Holt to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Jan 7; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - [Guy] Holt to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Jan 21; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1924 Jan 26; TLS, 1 p.
  - [Guy] Holt to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Feb 7; TL (carbon), 2 p.
  - [Guy] Holt to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Feb 11; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1924 Mar 8; TLS, 1 p.
  - [ Guy Holt] to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Mar 10; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1924 Mar 29; TLS, 1 p.
  - [ Guy Holt] to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Apr 9; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1924 Apr 11; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1924 Apr 19; TLS, 1 p.
  - [Guy] Holt to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Apr 22; TL (carbon), 2 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1924 Apr 26; TLS, 1 p.
  - [Guy] Holt to James Branch Cabell, 1924 May 3; TL (carbon), 2 p.
  - [Guy] Holt to James Branch Cabell, 1924 May 19; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1924 Jun 9; TLS, 1 p.
  - [Guy] Holt to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Jun 16; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1924 Jun 17; TL, 1 p.
  - [Guy] Holt to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Jun 19; TL (carbon), 2 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, [1924 Jun]; TLS, 1 p.
  - [Guy] Holt to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Jul 7; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to Mr. Tewson, 1924 Jul 27; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1924 Aug 18; TLS, 1 p.
    [On verso, TL (carbon), 1 p., [Guy] Holt to James Branch Cabell]
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1924 Sep 9; TLS, 1 p.
  - [Guy] Holt to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Sep 17; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1924 Sep 20; TLS, 1 p.
  - [Guy] Holt to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Sep 25; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1924 Oct 6; TLS, 1 p.
  - [Guy] Holt to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Oct 18; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1924 Oct 24; TLS, 1 p.
  - [Guy] Holt to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Oct 27; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1924 Oct 30; TLS, 1 p.
  - [Guy] Holt to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Oct 31; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1924 Nov 5; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1924 Nov 8; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1924 Dec 13; TLS, 1 p.
  - [Guy] Holt to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Dec 22; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - [Guy] Holt to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Jan 9; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - [Guy] Holt to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Jan 13; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1925 Jan 16; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1925 Jan 17; TLS, 1 p.
  - [Guy] Holt to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Jan 21; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - [Guy] Holt to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Jan 24; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - [Guy] Holt to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Feb 9; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1925 Feb 28; TLS, 1 p.
  - [Guy] Holt to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Mar 9; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1925 Mar 14; TLS, 1 p.
  - [Guy] Holt to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Mar 17; TL (carbon), 2 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1925 Mar 28; TLS, 1 p.
  - [Guy] Holt to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Apr 2; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1925 Apr 4; TLS, 1 p.
  - [Guy] Holt to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Apr 16; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1925 Apr 25; TLS, 1 p.
  - [Guy] Holt to James Branch Cabell, 1925 May 9; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1925 May 16; TLS, 1 p.
  - [Guy] Holt to James Branch Cabell, 1925 May 19; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1925 May 23; TLS, 1 p.
  - [Guy] Holt to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Jun 4; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1925 Jun 6; TLS, 1 p.
  - [Guy] Holt to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Jun 12; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to Tewson, 1925 Jun 20; TLS, 1 p.
  - [ Guy Holt] to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Jul 8; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1925 Sep 3; TLS, 1 p.
  - [Guy] Holt to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Sep 4; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1925 Sep 9; TLS, 1 p.
  - [Guy] Holt to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Sep 16; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - [Guy] Holt to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Sep 22; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1925 Sep 30; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1925 Sep 30; TLS, 2 p.
  - [Guy] Holt to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Oct 2; TL (carbon), 2 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1925 Oct 10; TLS, 1 p.
  - [ Guy Holt] to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Oct 17; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1925 Oct 25; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1925 Oct 29; TLS, 1 p.
  - [Guy] Holt to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Nov 2; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1925 Nov 3; TLS, 1 p.
  - [Guy] Holt to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Nov 5; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - [Guy] Holt to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Nov 5; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - [Guy] Holt to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Nov 12; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1925 Nov 14; TLS, 1 p.
  - [Guy] Holt to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Dec 8; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1925 Dec 16; TLS, 1 p.
  - [Guy] Holt to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Dec 17; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1925 Dec 23; TLS, 1 p.
  - [Guy] Holt to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Dec 31; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, [1925]; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1926 Feb 7; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1926 Feb 11; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1926 Mar 18; TLS, 2 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1926 Mar 22; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to Mr. Devlin, 1926 Mar 27; TLS, 1 p.
  - [Guy] Holt to James Branch Cabell, 1926 Apr 1; TL (carbon), 2 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1926 Apr 3; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1926 Oct 7; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1926 Oct 10; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1927 Jan 7; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1927 May 18; TLS, 1 p.
  - [Guy] Holt to James Branch Cabell, 1927 Jun 13; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1927 Jun 17; TLS, 1 p.
  - [Guy] Holt to James Branch Cabell, 1927 Jun 27; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1927 Oct 27; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1927 Dec 10; TLS, 1 p.
  - unknown to James Branch Cabell, 1928 Jun 4; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [James R.] Wells, 1928 Jun 6; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [James R.] Wells, 1928 Jun 26; TLS, 1 p. w/env
  - James Branch Cabell to [Crosby] Gaige, 1928 Jul 19; TLS, 1 p. w/env
  - James Branch Cabell to [Crosby] Gaige, 1928 Aug 4; TLS, 1 p. w/env
  - James Branch Cabell to [Crosby] Gaige, 1928 Aug 5; TLS, 1 p. w/env
  - W.A. Dwiggins to [Crosby] Gaige, [1928] Aug 8; ALS, 2 p.
    [re: the Cabell "Ballades"]
  - James Branch Cabell to [Crosby] Gaige, 1928 Aug 20; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Crosby] Gaige, 1928 Sep 10; TLS, 1 p. w/env
  - James Branch Cabell to [Crosby] Gaige, 1928 Sep 16; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Crosby] Gaige, 1928 Sep 23; TLS, 1 p.
  - Sinclair Lewis to Guy [Holt], 1929 Feb 28; TLS, 1 p.
  - [Guy] Holt to "Hal" [ Sinclair Lewis], 1929 Mar 5; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - [Guy] Holt to James Branch Cabell, 1929 Nov 29; TL, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1929 Dec 8; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1929 Dec 13; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1930 Feb 8; TLS, 1 p.
  - [Guy] Holt to James Branch Cabell, 1930 Mar 4; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1930 Mar 8; TLS, 1 p.
  - [Guy] Holt to James Branch Cabell, 1930 Mar 18; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1930 Mar 22; TLS, 1 p.
  - [Guy] Holt to James Branch Cabell, 1930 Apr 5; TL (carbon), 2 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1930 Apr 10; TLS, 1 p.
  - [Guy] Holt to James Branch Cabell, 1930 Apr 14; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1930 Apr 26; TLS, 1 p.
  - [Guy] Holt to James Branch Cabell, 1930 May 5; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1930 May 10; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1930 Jun 14; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to Mr. Drinkwater, 1931 Feb 21; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1932 Feb 26; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1932 Oct 18; TLS, 1 p.
  - Guy Holt to James Branch Cabell, 1932 Nov 12; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1933 Apr 12; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1933 Oct 7; TLS, 1 p.
  - [Guy] Holt to James Branch Cabell, 1933 Dec 13; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Guy] Holt, 1933 Dec 28; TLS, 1 p.
  - E. J. Halter to James Branch Cabell, 1946 Apr 10; TL (carbon), 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [E. J.] Halter, 1946 Apr 19; TLS, 1 p.
- Miscellaneous
  - News clipping, " Charles Hanson Towne Praises Romance of Cabell" from the Cincinnati Enquirer, 1913 Dec 13; Clipping
  - Typed biographical sketch of James Branch Cabell, 1917 Nov; Biographical sketch, 5 p.
  - News clipping, "The Artistic Temperament Again" from a signed review by Edwin Markham, ca. 1917; Clipping
  - Typed extracts from letters re: Cabell by Albert Bigelow Paine, Josephine Prescott Peabody and a review by H. L. Mencken, ca. 1917; Clippings
  - Typed note re: "the jackets of Chivalry & the Line of Love...", ca. 1917; Typed note
  - Miscellaneous clippings re: Jurgen, 1919; Clippings